(注意：本字幕不针对原版视频, 而是粉丝剪辑版本 http://wp.me/p1mHFo-m8 )
You may have been on duty all night, Fewsham,
你可能是值班值了一夜, Fewsham
but that's no excuse for this kind of slipping up!
但那也不能成为这种失误的借口！
They weren't major hold-ups. Just a few minutes.
并没有出现大的阻塞, 就几分钟而已
- Kelly was going mad back on Earth Control!
- She would!
- Kelly 在地球控制中心那边都发飙了  - 她的确会！
I'm sorry, Fewsham, but it's my head
in the noose as well, you know!
对不起, Fewsham, 但受责备的是我, 知道吗？
I know! I'm sorry.
我知道！对不起
Oh, all right.
哦, 算了
All right, go on. You'd better get back to Earth.
好吧, 继续．你最好回地球去
(WAILING BEEP)
Now what?!
怎么回事？
That's the air locks.
像是气闸那边的
- Who's there?
- No one.
- 谁在哪儿？  - 没谁
Then how come the air locks are in use?
那为什么气闸有人使用？
(MAN SCREAMS IN TERROR)
Phipps! What is it? What's happened?
Phipps！怎么回事？发生了什么？
Come on, man!
快点, 伙计！
(TERRIFIED SCREAM)
Close the door! We've got to keep...
把门关上！我们必须得...
(POUNDING, CLANGING FOOTSTEPS)
Don't move, anybody! Don't do anything!
别动, 所有人！什么也不要做！
Harvey, don't!
Harvey, 别！
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(POUNDING, CLANGING FOOTSTEPS)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
The Seeds of Death
死亡的种子
(Doctor Who 1963 06x05)
（神秘博士老版 第六季第五集）
（翻译: 巴蛮子sz ）
（时间轴: 巴蛮子sz ）
No! I refuse!
不, 我拒绝！
(RASPING WHISPER) You will be wise to co-operate at once,
聪明的话, 立即合作
otherwise you will be destroyed!
否则你就会被消灭！
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Well, I suppose that leaves me no alternative.
这, 我觉得我没有别的选择了
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Don't do it, sir!
别啊, 头儿！
(RASPING WHISPER) Silence!
安静！
There's a certain element of risk.
这里会有一定的风险
(RASPING WHISPER) You are wasting time!
你实在浪费时间！
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
(RASPING WHISPER) What is happening?
怎么回事？
I'm afraid there's been a fault.
恐怕这里出故障了
The circuit's overloaded.
线路过载了
Very unfortunate.
非常不幸
(RASPING WHISPER) You deliberately sabotaged this apparatus!
你蓄意破坏了这个装置！
Kill him!
杀了他！
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(JAMIE) Hey! Quite a place, isn't it?
嘿！不错的地方啊, 是不？
(DOCTOR) Oh, my word!
哦, 天哪
- Look at the size of this one, Doc!
- Yes!
- 看看这东西有多大, 博士！  - 是啊！
(ZOE) Oh, Doctor, look!
噢, 博士, 你看！
Doctor, look.
博士, 瞧瞧
Now, Zoe... (BEEPING)
现在, Zoe...
What's that?
什么东西？
(MAN) Travel Mat is the ultimate form of travel.
T-Mat 物传系统是传送物质的最终形式
Control centre of the present at the moment
is the moon, serving all major cities on Earth.
当前控制中心在月球上, 为地球各大城市提供服务
Travel Mat provides an instantaneous means of public travel,
T-Mat 物传系统提供一种即时传送能力
and transports raw materials and
vital food supplies to all parts of the world.
将原材料和重要的食物供应传送到世界各地
- (JAMIE) Travel Mat? Sounds like a flying carpet!
- Hush, hush, Jamie, keep silence
- 物传系统？听起来像是个飞毯! - 嘘, 嘘, Jamie, 安静
Travel Mat supersedes all conventional forms of transports
T-Mat 物传系统取代了所有传统形式的运输
using the principle of dematerialisation
at the point of departure,
它的工作原理是将物质在出发点进行反物质化分解
and rematerialisation at the point of arriva
l in special cubicles.
然后再在到达点的特殊格子间里面进行物质化聚合
Departure and arrival are almost instantaneous.
出发和到达基本上是瞬时的
Faster than light!
比光还快！
Although The system is still in its early stage,
虽然这个系统还在早期阶段
it is completely automated and
fool-proofed against power failure.
它已经实现完全自动化, 并且可以避免在停电时带来灾难
Well, we have our own system, thank you,
only it isn't foolproof!
哦, 谢谢你, 我们也有自己的系统,  只是它不太能防呆
Jamie, I think that's just a tiny bit...
Jamie, 我觉得那只是一个小问题...
You saw what happened to your superior.
你看到了你的上级怎么样了
You would do well to co-operate.
你会乖乖合作的
Killing him didn't do you any good.
杀死他不会给你们带来任何好处
- Would you do as I ask?
- There is nothing I can do!
- 你会按我的要求行事吗？  - 这里我做不了什么了
- You do not want to die?
- I'm not that good enough a technician!
- 你不想死吧？  - 我是个不怎么样的技工！
- It needs an expert!
- But you are second in command here.
- 这需要一个专家！  - 但你是这里的二把手
- Yes, but...
- You must have certain abilities.
- 是的, 但是...  - 你肯定有些能力
- You must know what needs to be done.
- In theory, yes.
- 你肯定知道需要搞定什么  - 理论上来说, 是的
Then you will do it!
那你就得做！
He'll only make it worse!
他只会把事情搞砸！
What is their status here?
他们在这里是做什么的？
Maintenance. Second-class technicians.
维护. 二级技工
There's only one person that could really put
all these things right, and she is at Earth Control.
只有一个人能让这一切恢复正常, 而她在地球控制中心
- Without her, it can't be done!
- Who is this specialist?
- 没有她, 这搞不定！  - 这个专家是谁？
Miss Kelly, technical co-ordinator.
Kelly 小姐, 技术协调员
But there's no way to reach her. T-Mat is not working.
但我们没法联系她, T-Mat 不工作了
- But you have a video link.
- Yes, but Osgood wrecked that, too!
- 但你们有视频线路  - 是的, 但 Osgood 把它也搞坏了！
So, there is no means to communicate with Earth?
这么说, 没有方法跟地球联系了？
No, you've cut us off completely!
没有, 你们把我们完全切断了！
In that case, you are useless!
这么说来, 你们都没有用了！
You will all be destroyed!
你们全部都要被消灭！
There's the emergency T-Mat link!
还有一条 T-Mat 紧急线路！
It only operates from here to Earth!
它只是供这里和地球之间使用的！
Then you will activate the apparatus...
那你激活这个装置...
..at once!
马上！
- It's damaged, too!
- The technicians will help repair it.
- 它也坏了！  - 技术人员将帮忙修好它
- We won't help you. Neither will he!
- Then he will die!
- 我们不会帮你的, 他也不会！  - 那他就死了！
No more money, no more facilities.
没有了钱, 也就没有了设备
A life's work abandoned, just like that.
All thanks to T-Mat!
一辈子的成果被遗弃了, 就这样．都拜 T-Mat 所赐!
I can understand your sense of bitterness, Professor.
我理解你的痛苦, 教授
Very short-sighted of the government
to put all their eggs in one basket!
目光短浅的政府把所有的鸡蛋放到了一个篮子里面！
You still haven't told me who you are
and what you're doing here!
你还没有告诉我你们是谁, 在这里干什么！
(WAILING BLEEP) That's the main door alarm!
What's going on?
那是主门在告警！怎么回事？
Professor Daniel Eldred, well, well, well!
Danile Eldred 教授, 好, 好, 好
Radnor, come to see how your spies are getting on?
Randor, 你是来看你那些间谍有什么进展的吗？
I'm sorry? We've not met.
My name's Radnor. This is Miss Kelly.
抱歉, 我们没见过．我叫 Radnor, 这是 Kelly 小姐
Oh, how do you do?
哦, 你好
This is Zoe, Jamie, and I'm the Doctor.
这是 Zoe, Jamie, 而我是博士
Don't pretend you don't know them!
别假装你不认识他们！
I can assure you I've never met them before in my life.
我可以保证我这辈子从来没有见过他们
I see. I find three strangers prowling around in my museum.
明白了．我发现这三个陌生人在我的博物馆里面鬼鬼祟祟
and by the merest coincidence,
you turn up on their very heels!
非常巧合的是, 你后脚就出现了
I can assure you I merely wanted a chat
with a very old friend.
我可以向你保证, 我只不过是想跟一个老朋友聊一聊
Well, you've done without a chat for a good many years.
噢, 很多年不聊你也过来了
Old times. Friendships don't die.
时光流逝, 但友情不会逝去
Our friendship ended the day
that you walked out of my laboratory
我们的友情在你走出我的实验室的时候就死了！
and joined the government administration on T-Mat!
在你加入政府的 T-Mat 管理方的时候就死了！
Different men, different careers!
不同的性格, 不同的职业发展！
Yes, but you knew which career
would be financed by government funds!
是, 但你却知道哪个职业会有政府投资！
You could have come over with me.
We are friends. You can join us.
你可以跟我一起来的啊, 我们是朋友, 你可以加入我们
Yes, and worked as Miss Kelly's assistant perhaps
是, 可以去当 Kelly 小姐的助手
You know I respect your work very much,
Professor Eldred.
你知道我一直都非常敬仰你的工作, Eldred 教授
We would have welcomed you on T-Mat.
我们一直都欢迎你加入 T-Mat
I prefer rockets, obsolete as they are!
我还是喜欢火箭, 不管它有多么过时！
Not so obsolete as all that, eh?
We don't miss very much, you know.
也不是那么过时, 也许？我们没有失去太多, 你知道吧
- So you've been spying on me!
- No, no no, we stopped that a long time ago.
- 看来你一直在监视我！  - 不, 不不, 我们很久以前就停掉了
I should think so?
What's wrong with running a private museum?
我该这么认为？办一个私人博物馆有什么错？
Nothing, but you're doing rather more than that, aren't you?
没什么错．但你办的不止是这个, 对不？
Alright, What if I am? It's a free country, isn't it?
What's wrong with having a hobby?
好吧, 是又怎么样？这是个自由的国家, 对吧？有一点个人爱好有什么错？
Rather more than a hobby
不只是一点个人爱好
preparing an ion rocket
for an unauthorised journey into space!
你是在准备离子火箭, 想用它未经许可就到太空去
All right, so you know.
好吧, 看来你知道
What do you intend to do?
你打算做什么？
- My dear fellow, help you, of course!  - What?
- 我亲爱的伙计, 当然是帮助你  - 什么？
You can make your trip, with full
Government backing.
你可以成行, 政府全力支持
- as long as it's to the moon.
- Why the moon?
- 只要目的地是月球  - 为什么是月球？
There's a minor fault developed
at T-Mat Control at Moonbase.
在月球基地的 T-Mat 控制中心出现了一点小故障
- And we had to put it right, quickly.
- I thought T-Mat was infallible!
- 我们必须得修复它, 还得快  - 我还以为 T-Mat 是绝不出错的
It will be eventually,
however we have no way of reaching the moon.
最终会的．目前而言, 我们没有办法到月球上去
Except by out-of-date rocket! Oh, that's perfect!
除非乘坐过时的火箭！哦, 太完美了！
You need me after all (!)
你最终还是需要我！
I thought you'd be taken with the idea,
我觉得你会喜欢这个想法
and a large sum of government funds
wouldn't come amiss, would they?
而且一大笔政府资金也不会花错地方, 是吧？
Now, how soon can you be ready to...blast off?
现在说是, 你最快多久可以准备好...发射？
Well, come on, it's urgent!
Can you give me an approximate ETD?
诶, 得了, 这是很紧急！你能给我一个大概的时间点吗？
I could, but I won't.
我能, 但我不会给
Why? There are no strings!
为什么？这里没有圈套！
I don’t have to give you my reasons.
I'm just telling you that I refuse!
我没有必要给出我的理由, 我只告诉你, 我拒绝！
- Right, that should do it.
- I'll switch on the power.
- 好, 这应该可以了  - 我去打开电源
You fools! When they find out, we'll all be killed!
你个蠢人！如果他们发现了, 我们都会被杀掉！
Moonbase to T-Mat Reception Earth.
月球基地呼叫 T-Mat 地球接收站
Moonbase to Earth.
月球基地呼叫地球
Emergency! Emergency!
紧急情况！紧急情况！
You can't refuse man. There’s more at stake here
than an out-of-date rocket programme!
你不能拒绝我．这里牵扯在内的因素很多, 不仅仅只是一个过时的火箭计划
- Commander Radnor.
- Excuse me.
- 指挥官 Radnor  - 抱歉
Radnor. Emergency message from Moonbase linking through now.
Radnor．月球基地请求建立紧急消息连接
Commander Radnor, Miss Kelly...
Radnor 指挥官, Kelly 小姐
..we are in desperate trouble!
Osgood is dead and we are...
..我们陷入了大麻烦！Osgood 已经死了, 而我们...
Locke! Locke!
Guard!
警卫！
Kill him!
杀了他！
Stop him!
拦住他!
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(RASPING WHISPER) Hunt that man!
He must not escape!
去找他！不能让他逃走！
Can we not help them? We can use the Tardis!
我们不能帮助他们吗？我们可以用 TARDIS!
To go to the moon? We'd probably overshoot
by a few million years!
到月球去吗？我们可能跑偏一百万年！
Yes, or by a few million miles!
是的, 或者是一百万英里！
I'm afraid the Tardis is not suited to short-range travel.
恐怕 TARDIS 不适合短途传送
Still I think we should help them if we can.
我仍然觉得我们应该尽我们所能帮助他们
- Aye.  - Yes.
- 对    - 是
- Well, I think I could get your rocket to the moon.  - You?
- 对了, 我觉得我可以把你的火箭弄到月球上去  - 你？
Yes, I have considerable experience in space travel,
and so have my two companions.
是的, 在太空旅行方面, 我有相当丰富的经验, 我这两位同伴也是
Doctor, that's splendid! Thank you!
博士, 那太棒了！谢谢你！
- But the rocket is not ready!
- Perhaps you overestimate the difficulty.
- 但火箭条件还不成熟  - 也许你高估了问题了难度
How much more work is required?
需要多少工作量？
It needs fuel and a complete computerised check.
需要燃料, 还需要用电脑进行一次完全的检查
- I can order that.
- No! I would not allow it! The risk is too great!
- 这我可以安排  - 不！我不允许！风险太大了
If there was some other way,
如果有其它的法子
- Believe me, I wouldn't even consider such a risk!  - No!
- 相信我, 我也不会考虑这么高风险的方法  - 不行！
(COMPUTER) Commander Radnor
Radnor 指挥官
Radnor. Go ahead.
我是 Radnor, 继续
T-Mat receptions - New York, Moscow, Tokyo -
各 T-Mat 接收站 - 纽约, 莫斯科, 东京
express great concern over continued hold-up.
都对持续停运表达的严正关切
Medical shipments and food awaiting
transit to Asiatic centres.
大批医疗用品和食物亟待传输到亚洲中心
Position desperate in Calcutta. Instructions awaited.
加尔各答情况危急. 等待指示
- That's your answer!
- Well, we want to help, as I said!
- 那就是你的答案！  - 我们的确想帮忙, 我说过了
You don't know what you're doing! It's suicide!
你不明白你在做什么！这是自杀！
Listen, if this fault lasts much longer,
听着, 如果这个故障继续往下拖着
there's going to be worldwide chaos,
and world population is at stake.
就会带来全世界的混乱, 所有地球人都受影响
Infallible T-Mat, putting the world in jeopardy!
恰是高可靠的 T-Mat, 把全世界推向了危机！
All right, I admit it.
好吧, 我承认
Now this man has to risk his life
to get you out of trouble!
现在这个人不得不押上自己的性命来解决你的麻烦
No, not for me, for thousands of people
all over the world
不, 不是为我, 是为了全世界成千上万的人
who will die if we don't take this risk!
我们不冒这个险他们就会死
I'm sorry, but I've got no alternative.
很抱歉, 我没有其他方案
- Miss Kelly.  - Sir.
- Kely 小姐  - 头儿
I want all technical personnel working on this.
我要所有的技术人员都扑到这上面
I want that rocket prepared for launching!
我要这架火箭可以发射！
Yes, Commander.
是, 指挥官
We'd be grateful for your help.
对于你的帮助, 我们很感激
If that rocket's to reach the moon safely,
you'll need more than my help...
要让那个火箭能安全到达月球, 你需要的不只是我的帮助...
You'll need a miracle!
你需要一个奇迹！
(RASPING WHISPER) Continue the search!
继续搜寻!
He must not escape!
不能让他逃走！
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
- Commander.
- Yes, Miss Kelly?
- 指挥官  - 什么事, Kelly 小姐？
Do you think it's wise letting
these people crew the rocket?
你觉得这样明智吗, 让这些人当火箭飞行员
Wise? No, of course it is not wise.
But what's the alternative?
明智？不, 当然不明智．但没有其它办法了啊
We gave up training astronauts years ago.
我们在多年以前就不再训练宇航员了
- But Who are they?
- Some of Eldred's crazy friends, I imagine,
- 但他们都是什么人？  - Eldred 的一些疯朋友吧, 我猜
But the man who calls himeself the Doctor
said he knows this space travel.
但那个自称博士的人说他懂太空旅行
- How can you be sure?
- You weren’t at the briefing,
- 你怎么能确定？- 做简报的时候你不在
He and the girl know more
about space flight than Eldred.
他和那个女孩儿在太空飞行方面比 Eldred 懂得多
- What about the boy?
- Yes, I'm not sure about him.
- 那那个男孩儿呢  - 是, 我对他不太有把握
(RASPING WHISPER) The emergency link with Earth,
跟地球的紧急连接
- is it ready yet?
- I've nearly finished.
- 好了没有？  - 我快完成了
- Do not make any mistakes!
- I'm not an expert!
- 不要出任何问题！  - 我不是个专家！
- But you will do it?
- Yes!
- 但你能做吗？  - 是的！
Commander, I think I should go as crew on the rocket.
指挥官, 我觉得我应该也到火箭上去
Don't be ridiculous, you're too valuable here!
别傻了, 你在这里太重要了！
How can T-Mat be repaired if I'm not there?
如果我不上去, T-Mat 怎么能修好呢？
- What about one of the technicians who was already over there?
- Osgood's dead.
- 已经在那边的技术人员都不行吗？  - Osgood 已经死了
- Yes, well, what about Fewsham?
- He's incapable of doing it! I think I should go!
- 是, 但是 Fewsham 怎么样？  - 他没有这个能力！我觉得我应该去！
No! You're the only one who really understands T-Mat.
不, 你是唯一真正懂 T-Mat 的人
I can't have you risking your life!
我不能让你拿你的性命去冒险！
But yet you are perfectly prepared
to allow them to risk theirs!
但你却允许他们拿性命去冒险！
Don't worry, Miss Kelly we'll be perfectly all right!
别担心, Kelly 小姐, 我们会完全没事的！
But I don't see what good just this emergency link can be.
但我看不出这个紧急连接能有什么用
Even if you had a gigantic army of warriors,
就算你有一只庞大军队, 全都是勇士
you couldn't send them all to conquer Earth.
你也不能把他们都送过去征服地球
(RASPING WHISPER) We do not need an army.
我们不需要一只军队
Earth will be ours for the taking...
地球会是我们的...
(HISSING BREATHING) ..very soon!
...很快就是！
- Doctor...  - Yes?
- 博士...  - 什么事？
Final check on procedure after you land.
最后核对一遍你着陆后的程序
Yes, I know. We're to re-establish
video link with the Earth.
是的, 我知道. 我们要重新建立与地球的视频连接
That's right.
对的
When we can see what's wrong,
一旦我们看出是什么地方出了问题
you can do the rest under Miss Kelly's supervision.
剩下的事你们就可以在 Kelly 小姐的指导下完成了
Right. We're ready when you are.
对．你们准备好了我们就发射了
12...
10...
nine...eight...seven...
9...8...7...
..six...five...four...three...
..6...5...4...3...
..two...one.
..2...1.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
It's done.
搞定了
- The emergency link will work now.
- Excellent!
- 紧急连接可以工作了  - 非常好！
- What are you going to do?
- Do not ask questions!
- 你打算做什么？  - 不许提问！
Activate the link.
激活连接
- On receive only.
- Receive?
- 设定为仅仅接收  - 接收？
But aren't you going to send...?
但你们不是要传送...？
Activate the link on receive at once!
将连接设置为仅接收, 立刻！
- (KELLY) You've double-checked everything?
- Yes, the fault is definitely on Moonbase.
- 都再三核对过了吧？  - 是的, 故障肯定在月球基地上
Is it possible for you to effect repairs over video?
你有可能通过视频指导完成修复吗？
Provided the fault is not too major.
除非不是什么大故障
And provided they actually get there with the rocket!
还得他们乘坐火箭真的能到那儿
- They'll get there
- Why? How do you know?
- 他们会到那里的 - 为什么？你怎么知道？
You can't even be sure
the rocket's still in one piece!
你都不能确定那火箭是不是还是完整一块！
- Miss Kelly!
- What is it, Brent?
- Kelly 小姐！  - 什么事, Brent？
We've got through. The emergency T-Mat link
to Moon Control is activating!
我们接通了．与月球控制中心的 T-Mat 紧急连接正在激活！
Is someone coming through?
有谁过来吗？
No, it's on send.
不, 设定在上传模式了
Moonbase must has managed to make a temporary repair.
月球基地肯定是设法临时修复了部分功能
It's all we need. Brent, have a full emergency kit waiting.
这也够了．Brent, 准备好全套紧急救援设备
- I'll join you as soon as possible.
- Yes, Miss Kelly. Standing by.
- 我随后就来   - 好的, Kelly 小姐. 我们待命
Where do you think you are going?
你觉得你是要去哪儿？
If we can send, it's the only thing I can do.
如果我们能发送, 我就只能做这件事情了
You have no idea what conditions are like up there!
你根本不清楚那上面到底什么情况！
I know all too well what are like down here
但我清楚地知道这下面都是什么情况了
Commander, you've stopped me once.
指挥官, 你阻拦了一次
Please don't try it again,
otherwise I shall have to go above your head.
请不要再这样了, 否则我就不得不越级了
- She's after your job, Julian!
- Miss Kelly!
- 她要挑战你的位置了, Julian!  - Kelly 小姐!
(TRILLING TONE)
- Thank heavens you've come!
- What happened?
- 感谢上天你来了!  - 什么情况?
Osgood, it must have been space madness.
Osgood 他肯定是出现了太空症状了,
He just went berserk! Pretty mad.
It was terrifying.
他直接就发狂了！太疯狂了, 非常吓人
Osgood? But he'd be the last man, I'd have thought!
Osgood？但他应该是最不可能的, 我一直这么以为！
- So did we.
- Where are the others?
- 我们也是  - 其他人在哪儿？
When Osgood fused the controls,
Locke tried to stop him.
Osgood 破坏控制系统的时候, Locke 试着阻止他
- Osgood killed him.
- This is fantastic!
- Osgood 杀了他  - 这太不可思议了！
- What about Phipps?
- He was injured too and I put him under sedation.
- Phipps 怎么样了  - 他也受伤了, 我给他用了镇静剂
- And you?
- There's nothing wrong with me.
- 你呢？  - 我没什么事
You look frightened.
你看起来吓坏了
If you'd seen Osgood die, wouldn't you be?
如果你见到 Osgood 死, 你不会吗？
How did he die?
他怎么死的？
His body's outside.
他的尸体在外面
He just went out.
他就那么出去了
Without a pressure suit? I see.
没穿压力服？我明白了
Open all control sections and computer links.
打开所有控制区域和电脑连接
Fewsham, what are you doing?
Fewsham, 你在做什么？
I thought I'd best switch off the emergency link.
我觉得我最好还是关掉紧急连接
- The trouble we've got could easily burn itself out.
- Sensible.
- 我们目前的问题很可能导致它烧坏  - 有道理
Anyway, it will prevent Commander Radnor
sending up another security guard
而且, 这样也能阻止指挥官 Radnor 派一个安全人员上来
to drag me back to Earth!
把我拖回地球去！
(RASPING WHISPER) The other human is still free. Find him!
另外一个人还在逃, 找到他！
He must not interfere with our plans!
不能让他干扰我们的计划！
Hello, Earth Control, this is Moonbase.
哈罗, 地球控制中心, 这里是月球基地
Emergency! Emergency! How do you read me?
紧急状况！紧急状况！你们能听到吗？
Hello, Earth Control, this is Moonbase.
哈罗, 地球控制中心, 这里是月球基地
Emergency! Emergency! Can you hear me?
紧急状况！紧急状况！你们能听到吗？
Hello, Moonbase! Can you hear ME?
哈罗, 月球基地! 你们能不能听到我？
Yes!
能！
Yes, I can hear you loud and clear!
能, 你的声音很清楚很响亮！
What part of Earth are you speaking from?
你是在地球上哪个位置说话？
(DOCTOR) We're not on the Earth.
We're in a rocket orbiting the moon.
我们不在地球上, 我们在一架火箭上, 目前正在月球轨道
A rocket? But that's impossible!
火箭？这不可能啊！
I can assure you it's not impossible!
What is your emergency?
我可以向你保证这不是不可能！你的紧急状况是什么？
What's happening on Moonbase?
月球基地发生了什么事情？
We've been invaded! Aliens have taken over!
我们被入侵了！外星人占领了这里！
Put that cover back on.
把那个盖子放回去
T-Mat back to Earth and report to Commander Radnor.
传送回地球, 向指挥官 Radnor 汇报
(RASPING WHISPER)
Stop!
停下！
You will remain here!
你得待在这里！
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Doctor, these aliens he described...
博士, 他说描述的外星人...
- Yes, Ice Warriors!
- What?
- 是了, 寒冰勇士！  - 什么？
Jamie and I have met them before.
They come from the planet Mars.
Jamie 和我之前跟他们遭遇过．他们来自火星
- What do they want?
- Mars is a dying planet.
- 他们想要什么？  - 火星是个要死的星球了
- I imagine that they want a new home.
- Why the moon?
- 我估计他们是想要一个新家  - 为什么选月球？
- I think it's just a stepping stone.
- What did you say? They're...Ice Warriors?
- 我想这只是一个垫脚石  - 你说他们叫什么来着, 是叫...寒冰勇士？
Yes, you know, Mars is a cold planet
and they've adapted to that.
是的, 你看, 火星是个寒冷的星球, 他们已经习惯了
It's heat they can't stand.
所以他们忍受不了炎热
We should just about be coming into range now.
我们现在应该快到地方了
Hello, Moonbase.
你好, 月球基地
(RASPING WHISPER) You will remain here!
你得待在这里！
That's the lot. The whole system's
completely operational again.
就这么些了. 整个系统已经完全恢复可用了
We can now send to any city in the world?
我们现在可以传送物品到世界上任何一个城市了？
- Yes, anywhere with a T-Mat centre.
- 是的, 只要这个城市有 T-Mat 中心
- Fewsham, Do you realise what you're doing?!
- I'm trying to save our lives!
- Fewsham, 你知道你在干什么吗？！  - 我尽力在救我们的命！
- Then what about the lives of the people on Earth?
- We're in no position to argue!
- 那地球上那么多人的命怎么办？  - 我们现在没资格讨价还价！
Why do you want control of T-Mat?
你们为什么想要控制 T-Mat？
If you're going to invade the Earth,
如果你们想要入侵地球
you'll be fighting the armed forces
of the entire world.
会有整个世界的武装力量同你们斗争
You'll never succeed. There'll be too much resistance.
你们不会成功的, 会有太多的反抗
There will be no resistance!
不会有任何反抗！
What about us? What will happen to us?
我们怎么办？我们会怎么样？
You will remain alive as long as you are useful.
你们的命会留着, 只要你们还有用
You'll never get any help from me.
你们永远别想从我这里得到帮助
When the time comes, you will do
exactly what you are told...
等时间到了, 你会按我们说的照做的
..or die!
..不然就死！
Hello?
哈罗？
- Who are you?
- Oh!
- 你是谁？  - 噢！
- Mr Phipps, I presume?
- Yes, but where did you come from?
- Phipps 先生, 我估计？  - 是的, 不过你们从哪儿来？
From the rocket. We were talking on the radio.
从火箭啊, 我们在无线电里说过了
- Thank heavens you've made it. Are the others here too?
- Yeah, They're still in the rocket.
- 感谢上天你们成功了．还有其他人吗？  - 有, 他们还在火箭里面
- How many Ice Warriors are there?
- Those creatures you mean?
- 这里有多少寒冰勇士？  - 你是说那些怪物吗？
- Not many, but they're deadly.
- They have their weak points.
- 不多, 不过他们很致命  - 他们有他们的弱点
Look, they've killed everybody here,
except Fewsham, who's helping them.
看, 他们已经杀了这里所有的人, 除了 Fewsham, 他在帮助他们
I see. Well, there's only one thing for it.
我明白了．这么说, 就只有一件事可干
- We shall have to destroy T-Mat.
- 我们必须得破坏 T-Mat
You will shortly dispatch a cargo
to certain cities on Earth.
很快你要发送一个货物到地球上的某个城市
Cargo? What sort of cargo?
货物？什么样的货物？
That's an Ice Warrior.
It's got Miss Kelly, but how...?
那就是寒冰勇士.  它抓住了 Kelly 小姐, 但怎么...？
Run!
跑！
Oh!
噢！
Stop!
停下！
(RASPING WHISPER) You must be destroyed!
必须消灭你！
You've got no orders to kill me!
你没有得到要杀死我的命令！
Your leader will want to speak to me!
你的头领想要同我谈谈的！
Humans are our enemies!
人类都是我们的敌人！
But I can be useful to you, like Fewsham!
但我对你们是有用的, 就像 Fewsham！
Your leader will be angry with you
if you kill me! I'm a genius!
如果你杀了我, 你的头领会发怒的！我是个天才！
(RASPING WHISPER) Genius!
天才！
You will come with me!
你跟我来！
The prisoner Kelly has escaped.
俘虏 Kelly 逃走了
This human was in the corridors.
这个人在走廊里
Who are you? Where are you from?
你是谁？你从哪里来？
I might ask you the same question!
我正想问你同样的问题！
You will find the human Kelly
and bring her back here!
如果你找到 Kelly 那个人类, 把她带回来！
- Who is this man?
- He's not one of the crew.
- 这个人是谁？  - 他不是我们组员之一
I don't know this man.
He must have just arrived here.
我不认识这个人, 他肯定是刚刚到这里的
Impossible - we control T-Mat.
How did you get here?
不可能 - 我们控制了 T-Mat．你怎么到这里的？
Our resources are not limited
to T-Mat, you know!
我们的资源可不止是 T-Mat, 你知道不？
- You arrived by other means? By space craft?
- Rockets haven't been used for years.
- 你用其它方法到这里的？坐宇宙飞船？  - 已经很多年不用火箭了
Then you are lying!
那你在撒谎！
You have been concealed here all the time.
你一直都躲在这里某个地方
(DOCTOR) But you can't be sure of that, can you, hmm?
但你还是没把握, 对不, 嗯？
The people of the Earth
地球上的人
may be preparing a whole fleet
of rockets to defend themselves with!
正在准备一整只火箭大军, 要保卫他们自己！
(ICE WARRIOR) No, Earth relies entirely on T-Mat.
不, 地球完全依赖于 T-Mat
There is no defence against our plans.
没有任何防御可以抵抗我们的计划
And what are your plans? Invasion by T-Mat?
你们的计划是什么？用 T-Mat 入侵？
There are too few of you to conquer
all the people of the Earth.
但你们人太少了, 没法征服地球上这么多人
(ICE WARRIOR) The Grand Marshall
has ordered the seeds to be prepared!
大元帅已经下令, 准备好种子
- You are to receive your instructions.
- Then guard the humans.
- 你要去接收指示  - 看好这些人类
If they try to escape, kill them!
如果他们打算逃跑, 杀了他们！
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Why are you helping them?
你为什么要帮他们？
I've seen what they can do!
我见过了他们的能耐！
Do you know what is in that container?
你知道那容器里面是什么吗？
All I know is they want me to send
something to Earth by T-Mat.
我只是知道他们想要我用 T-Mat 传送什么东西到地球上去
- I suppose that's what's in it.
- I shall have to look inside,
- 我估计就是那里面的东西  - 我打算去看一眼
and you are going to help me!
而你要帮我！
The Doctor's been captured?
But couldn't you help him?
博士被抓住了？你们不能帮他吗？
I'm sorry, but there was nothing we could do.
抱歉, 但当时我们也没辙
- We had a job to reach here ourselves.
- Aye. So did we!
- 我们到这里也是有任务的  - 嗯, 我们也是！
Are you sure the Ice Warriors
don't know about this place?
你确定寒冰勇士不知道这个地方？
- One of them did find it, but I managed to deal with it.
- How?
- 其中一个还真发现了, 但我设法搞定它了  - 怎么搞定的?
I fixed up some kind of a booby trap
to the solar energy power line.
但我用太阳能电源的电力设了一个诱杀机关
It looks those things are invulnerable!
看起来他们是刀枪不入的！
- No, the Doctor said they can't stand heat.
- That's right!
- 不, 博士说他们忍受不了热  - 对！
The heating system of the entire base
is controlled from the Centre.
这整个基地的供热系统都是在中心控制的
Now if we can reach those control,
we can turn up the heating.
如果我们能够得着那些控制, 我们就可以调高温度
But how can we get there?
Ice Warriors are patrolling those corridors.
但我们怎么到那里呢？这些走道里都有寒冰勇士在巡逻
Aye, Yes I know. The maintenance tunnel's over here!
是, 我知道．这里有维修通道！
(WHISPERS) All right, Fewsham, now!
好了, Fewsham, 动手！
I can't! They'll kill us both!
我不能！他们会把我们俩都杀了！
- You've got to help me!
- I can't, I daren't.
- 你必须帮我！  - 我不能, 我不敢！
Very well, I shall do it by myself.
好吧, 那我就自己干
If I am caught, which is most likely,
we will both get killed.
如果我被抓了, 这非常可能发生, 我们俩都会被杀
(RASPING WHISPER) Do not move!
不许动！
I was ordered to prepare the controls for transmission.
I’ve got to check that everything is in order.
我被要求准备传送控制, 我得检查一下所有东西是不是正常
(RASPING WHISPER) Return to where you were!
回到你原来的地方去！
(FEWSHAM) But this is most important!
但这事情很重要！
If you are trying to escape, I shall destroy you!
如果你是打算逃跑, 我会灭了你！
I'm not trying to escape!
我没打算逃跑！
Go back to where you were!
回到你原来的地方！
All right! All right!
好吧, 好吧！
Wait!
等一下！
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Open it!
打开它！
I said, ''Open it''!
我说了, ＂打开它＂！
What are these things?
这些是什么东西？
They look like seed pods.
看起来像是种子荚
(CHOKING COUGH)
(FEWSHAM) What is it?
What's happened to him?
他怎么了？
Is he dead?
他死了吗？
We can get through it here then.
Turn the heating up, knock the Warriors out
我们可以从这里过去, 调高温度, 敲晕寒冰勇士
- We can rescue the Doctor.
- And T-Mat ourselves back to Earth.
- 我们就可以救出博士 - 然后再用 T-Mat 传送回地球
- But I thought that T-Mat's broken down.
- Not any more, I repaired it.
- 但我记得 T-Mat 坏掉了  - 不再是了, 我修好了
Can we get this cover off?
你能把这个盖子拿掉吗？
This part of the base has been disused for ages.
It's rusted. It will take some time.
基地的这一片已经很久没有使用了, 都锈了, 要点时间
The Doctor may not have much time.
博士可能没有太多时间
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
You will prepare to activate the cubicle
and transmit to London.
你准备好, 马上要激活格子间, 传送物品去伦敦
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING) Obey!
服从！
Activate!
激活！
(TRILLING HUM)
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
Commander Radnor! T-Mat is working.
指挥官 Radnor！ T-Mat 正在工作
- Working? Kelly must have got through!
- Splendid!
- 工作！Kelly 肯定要过来了  - 太好了
What is it?
这是什么？
It's alive! The thing's alive!
它是活的, 这东西是活的！
(COUGHING)
He's dead!
他死了！
Keep back! It must be that smoke!
后退！肯定是这种烟雾！
(COUGHS)
Guards!
警卫！
(CHOKING COUGH)
Keep away from here!
别靠近这里！
Use the air conditioning!
打开空调！
Switch the air conditioning to expel!
将空调切到排烟模式！
(DRONING AND BUZZING)
(RASPING WHISPER) Dispose of him!
处理掉他！
- What do you mean?
- You will adjust the T-Mat controls
- 你什么意思？  - 你要调节 T-Mat 开关
and suspend him in space...
把他仍到太空中去...
..between the moon and Earth!
..在月球与地球的中央！
- Is this the right cubicle?
- It had better be!
- 就是这个格子间吗？  - 最好就是！
(FEWSHAM) Please! Please don't make me!
求你了！请别逼我！
Complete it!
快完成！
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Oh, no!
噢, 不要！
That's the interior casing.
It comes off easily.
那是内部套管, 很容易弄下来的
- Is the circuit prepared yet?
- Yes, almost.
- 线路准备好了吗？  - 是, 快了
- Almost.
- You are wasting time!
- 就快完成了  - 你在拖延时间！
- Operate!
- No!
- 操作！  - 不！
At once!
立即！
(TRILLING)
You've killed him!
你杀了他！
You've killed him! You've killed him!
你杀死了他！你杀死了他！
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
(RASPING WHISPER) Prepare to dispatch to London.
准备传送到伦敦
Do as I say!
按我说的做！
The time has come for your mission.
You understand what you must do?
是时候了, 你的人物该开始了．你明白你必须做什么吗？
I understand. (HISSES)
我明白
You must succeed at all costs.
你必须成功, 不惜一切代价
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Transmit to London!
传送到伦敦！
I need time.
我需要时间
I must reprogramme.
需要重新编制程序
(COMPUTER) Information coming in
on appearance of vegetable blight
收到信息：出现蔬菜疫情
attacking parks and gardens
in the metropolises.
各大都市的公园和花园均有出现
(RADNOR) Guards!
警卫
(COMPUTER) ..destroying cereals.
...毁坏了谷类作物
(TRILLING BUZZ)
How much longer must I wait here?
我还得在这里等多久？
(RASPING WHISPER) Do not ask questions!
不许问问题！
I need food and rest!
我需要食物, 还有休息！
I haven't had any sleep for...
我已经很久没有睡觉了
..hours.
很多个小时
(RASPING WHISPER) What are you doing?
你在干什么？
I must fix the cubicle.
我必须先修好传送格子间
But you said T-Mat was functioning properly!
但你说过 T-Mat 工作很正常！
I know, but there's something I forgot.
我知道, 但有点情况我忘记了
Quick! The heating controls are over there.
快！温度调节齐就在那里
Turn the main wheel to full.
将最大那个轮子转到最大
Report to Central Control.
报告控制中心
The creature is entering the east compound area.
那个怪物已经进入了东部大院
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(RADNOR) What's happened? Report!
什么情况？赶紧报告！
Look out, Zoe!
小心, Zoe！
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(part4 ends here)
Doctor! Are you all right?
博士！你没事吧？
- Yes, I am. I think so.
- Where's Phipps?
- 是的, 没事, 我觉得是 - Phipps 哪儿去了？
He's dead. An Ice Warrior killed him.
他死了, 一个寒冰勇士杀了他！
How did you manage to escape?
你怎么逃出来的？
- The other man helped me.
- Fewsham? I thought he was working for them
- 另外那个人帮了我  - Fewsham？之前我认为他在为他们工作
- He saved my life.
- Doesn't sound much like Fewsham.
- 他救了我的命  - 听起来不像是 Fewsham
He attacked the Ice Warrior.
He's also got T-Mat working again./?
他袭击了寒冰勇士, 还把 T-Mat 修好了
(DOCTOR) Do I gether we can get back to Earth?
我可以理解为我们可以回地球了？
- I think so.
- Let's not waste any more time!
- 我觉得是  - 那我们不要再浪费时间了！
(Weather Control Center)
（气候控制中心）
（四个推杆上面的文字：DRY - 干燥）
（装置主体上文字: Weather Control Unit - 气候控制器)
I had to help them or they would have killed me!
我不得不帮助他们, 否则他们就会杀了我！
All right, Fewsham. There'll be a full inquiry
when we get back to Earth. Tell them.
好了, Fewsham．等我们回到地球, 会有一个完整的听证会的．跟他们说吧
No more time to waste.
We must T-Mat back to Earth immediately.
不要再浪费时间了, 我们必须立即用 T-Mat 传送回地球
But if we all are going, who is going to dispatch us?
但如果我们都走的话, 谁来控制设备送我们走啊
There's a way of doing that. Here, this time switch
delays transportation by ten seconds.
有一个方法可以搞定．这里, 这个延时器可以将传送延迟１０秒
- Oh, I see, how genius.
- I'll dispatch you and follow you using the time switch.
- 哦, 明白了, 很天才  - 我先送你们走, 然后我再用延时器过来
Right, so Zoe, Jamie, come along.
I think this could be quite fun!
好, Zoe, Jamie, 都过来．我觉得这肯定很有意思！
Fewsham, that time switch was down
on the maintenance report for being inoperable.
Fewsham, 维护记录里面说那个延时器已经坏了不能使用
We repaired it!
我们已经修好了
(TRILLING)
In you get, Miss Kelly.
I'll use the time switch.
你进去, Kelly 小姐．我后面用延时器过来
You better hurry.
Those Ice Warriors will be back any minute.
你最好快点, 那些寒冰勇士随时都可能回来
Do you know, I find T-Mat travel rather disappointing.
知道吗, 我发现 T-Mat 旅行很让人失望
There's no sensation at all!
完全一点感觉都没有
Where have you been?
And what were you being up to all this time?
你们去哪儿了？这半天你们都在干什么？
Where's... Miss Kelly! What's happening up there?
哪儿... Kelly 小姐！上面发上了什么？
Will someone tell me what's happening down here?!
有没有谁能告诉我这里发生了什么？
Who are these people? Is T-Mat working?
这些人是谁？T-Mat 能工作了吗？
Now, please, don't...
Let us just one question at a time!
好了, 停停, 别... 我们一个个问题来！
Doctor, do you know there's been an alien here?
博士, 你知道这里出现了一个外星人吗？
- An Ice Warrior HERE?!
- Jamie, I am not surprised.
- 这里有了寒冰勇士？！  - Jamie, 我并不奇怪
They have taken over the whole Moonbase.
他们已经完全占领了月球基地
- What about the crew?
- All dead except Fewsham.
- 组员都怎么样了？  - 除了 Fewsham, 都死了
- You left him there?
- He said he'd follow using the time switch.
- 你们把他丢在哪儿了？  - 他说他随后就来, 用延时器
He should be back.
他会回来的
What's happening?
什么情况？
I thought so! The time switch is still out of order.
如我所料, 延时器仍然是坏的
- What? But he said he had repaired it.
- He was lying.
- 什么？但他说他修好了它  - 他在撒谎
- Why?  - Obviously he's working for them!
- 为什么？  - 很显然, 他在为他们做事！
Then why did he let us escape?
那他为什么又让我们逃走？
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
But don't you see, gentlmen?
你们没看出来吗, 先生们？
The invasion of Moonbase,
the taking over of T-Mat, the seed pods,
入侵月球基地, 占领 T-Mat, 还有这些种子
the arrival of the Ice Warrior,
they're all part of the same plan.
派遣寒冰勇士过来, 这些都是同一计划中的一部分
Plan? What plan?
计划？什么计划？
These incidents seem unrelated.
这些事件看起来都是不相关的
This fungus everywhere,
what's that got to do with it?
到处都有的泡沫, 跟这一切又有什么关系？
I'm not quite sure yet. Have your people
been able to make anything of it?
我也还不太确定．你们研究明白一点什么了没有？
It's indestructible. We've attacked it
with every possible way, but without success.
消灭不了它, 我们用尽了各种方法攻击它, 但都没有成效
Yes, but have you tried to UNDERSTAND it?
是, 但你们有没有试过＂了解＂它？
You suggest we should psychoanalyse it, Doctor?
你是说我们应该对它进行心里分析吗, 博士？
I'm merely suggesting that rather than destroy it,
you should find out its composition and purpose.
我只不过是说, 除了消灭它, 你们应该搞明白它的组成和目的
I have some laboratory equipment
in my workshop. You could use that.
我的工作室有一些实验设备, 你可以用
- Good. Then we need a sample.
- No problem about that.
- 很好, 然后我们需要一个样本  - 这没问题
- The gardens are full of the stuff.
- Fine. The let no time to be lost.
- 花园里面到处都是  - 好, 那就抓紧时间吧
I'll get some equipment for you.
我去给你拿些设备
Doctor, do be careful. Those pod things are deadly.
博士, 千万小心．那些夹子很致命的
Don't worry. I've already had experience.
I'll be careful.
别担心, 我已经有些经验了, 我会小心的
(DOCTOR) Yes... It's organic.
嗯... 这是有机的
It's alive.
是活的
It's definitely a fungus composition.
这绝对是一种真菌组织
- Are you sure this is correct?
- As far as I can make out, it is.
- 你确定这是对的吗？  - 就我目前的理解, 是的
A molecule of five atoms...absorbs oxygen.
由五个原子组成的一个分子...会吸收氧气
You know, a complete blanket of this
你知道吗, 一大片这样的东西
would reduce the oxygen content
of the Earth's atmosphere drastically.
就会显著降低地球空气中的氧气浓度
According to my calculations,
to one twentieth normal.
根据我的计算, 会降到 5% 的水平
It would make the Earth's atmosphere
uninhabitable to the human race,
这会使得地球的大气不再适合人类居住
but exactly like the atmosphere of Mars!
而是变得跟火星的大气一模一样！
Look at that. Even without vegetation
to feed on, it's still active. Oh!
看这个, 即使不蚕食植物, 它还是活着的．噢！
(ELDRED) If that thing explodes here,
the fumes will kill us! Come on, Doctor!
如果那个东西在这里爆炸, 那种烟会杀死我们的！快闪, 博士！
Just a minute. There must be some way of...
等一下, 肯定有某种方法...
- (ELDRED) Come on!
- (DOCTOR) Sulphuric acid!
- 快点！  - 硫酸！
Hydrochloric acid!
盐酸！
Acetic acid!
乙酸！
(ELDRED) You've done it!
你搞定了！
Well, what was it? What did you throw on it?
哦, 那是什么？你倒了什么东西上去？
- You really think it would work?
- Well It could be less effective than Moonbase, of course.
- 你真的觉得这能行？  - 它可能没有月球基地那么有效, 当然的
which handles up to two million
microwave channels simultaneously,
月球基地可以同时支持二百万的微波通道
the satellite would just take a few thousand.
而卫星只能支持几千
That would be enough for vital food supplies.
用来传送重要食物供应那也够了
But we can't use normal communications satellites.
They are not programmed for T-Mat.
但我们不能使用普通的通讯卫星啊, 它们不是为 T-Mat 准备的
No. We have to send up a specially programmed one.
的确不是, 我们得单独发射一颗, 经过特殊编程的
That would mean using a rocket, wouldn't it?
I thought no one use them nowadays.
但那意味着要使用火箭, 对不对？我记得现在都没人使用了？
Not manned rockets, but we do send up
satellites for communications.
是没有载人火箭, 但我们还是会用它发射通讯卫星
- How soon can you get one up?
- Well, I don't know. If we're given top priority...
- 多久你们能搞一个上天？  - 嗯, 我不知道．如果我们被授予最高优先级...
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
There!
那儿！
(FEWSHAM) What is it?
什么东西？
A communications unit from our ship.
一个通讯装置, 可以联系我们的飞船
Connect it to the solar batteries!
把它连到太阳能电池上去
(DOCTOR) Is Commander Radnor there, please?
Radnor 指挥官在, 请问？
- Oh, Zoe, is Radnor there?
- He's in conference with Miss Kelly and Sir James Gregson.
- 哦, Zoe, Radnor 在吗？  - 他正在跟 Kelly 小姐和 James 爵士开会
Oh, I see. Zoe. There's the most wonderful news!
哦, 我知道了, Zoe．现在有一个非常好的消息！
We've found a way of destroying the fungus!
我们找到了一种消灭泡沫的方法！
- Oh! What is it?
- Water! Ordinary water!
- 噢, 什么方法？  - 水！普通水！
- Oh, Doctor, surely...
- There's no time to explain now.
- 哦, 博士, 当然...  - 现在没有时间详细解释了
Apparently, there is a Weather Control Bureau somewhere.
显然, 这里某个地方有一个气象控制局
I want you to get in touch with them.
我期望你去联系一下他们
Can't you reach them on the video phone?
你不能通过视频电话联系他们吗？
No, I've tried. They are not answering,
or it's broken down or something.
不能, 我试过了．他们没接, 或许是什么地方坏了
- What do you want me to do?
- Get hold of the Weather Control Bureau people
- 你期望我做什么  - 联系上气象控制局的人
and to make rain, as much rain as possible
over the entire country!
让他们造雨, 在全国范围内越多的雨越好！
- Well, where is everybody?
- I don't know.
- 咦, 人都哪儿去了  - 我不知道
Let's find the main control room. Come on.
我们先找主控室吧, 快点
So that's why no one answered the video phone.
怪不得没人接视频电话了
And look at that!
快看那个！
No, it's no good. They're locked in position.
不, 这没用, 他们的位置被锁死了
Our fleet is approaching
the gravitational field of the moon.
我们的舰队已经接近月球的引力范围
- Is all prepared?
- Everything is ready.
- 都准备好了吗？  - 都准备好了
I shall guide our ships in on the homing beam signal.
我将用指引信号引导我们的飞船过来
(BEEPING) What the devil's happening?
都什么鬼？
I don't know... Yes, Moon Control!
我不知道... 是了, 月球控制中心！
The sound, can you turn it up?
那个声音, 你能调大一点吗？
Shouldn't we test the directional beam?
我们不测试一下牵引光速吗？
- It is not necessary!
- But it's operating on Moonbase power.
- 这没有必要！  - 但它在耗用月球基地的能量
I can't guarantee the pulsing rate will be the same.
我不能保证脉动率会是一样的
Very well. Test it!
那好, 测试！
Commander Radnor, can this be recorded?
Radnor 指挥官, 能把这录下来吗？
- Yes.  - Quickly! Manage it. It's vital!
- 可以  - 快！安排一下, 这至关重要！
The transmission coming in
on the video machine would be recorded.
记录视频系统传送过来的信息
(COMPUTER) Instruction Understood.
Transmission will be recorded.
指令已经收到．信息将会被记录
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
(ICE WARRIOR) The device is operating.
设备在运转了
Wait a moment!
等一下！
Um...I must check the connections.
唔...我必须坚持一下连接
(SIGNAL CONTINUES)
If the power fails, we won't be able
to guide the fleet onto the moon.
如果电源失效, 我们就无法引导舰队到月球上了
There must be no failures!
那就必须没有失效！
I realise the importance of that.
If we overshoot the moon,
我明白这个的重要性．如果我们跑偏了
nothing will stop them from going
straight into an orbit around the sun.
他们就会直接进入太阳轨道, 没有什么能拦得住
They will not overshoot!
他们不会跑偏！
Of course not, but since their fuel
supplies are at a marginal level,
当然不会, 但他们的燃料并不是太多
if anything did go wrong,
they'd never be able to regain moon orbit.
如果出现什么意外, 他们无法重新进入月球轨道
This video device is operating!
这个视频设备在运转！
You have betrayed us!
你背叛了我们！
- Every word has been heard on Earth!
- Kill him!
- 每句话都被地球人听到了  - 杀了他！
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(COMPUTER) Countdown in minus three minutes.
三分钟内开始倒计时
Cancel the launch! We can use that
satellite to mislead the Martian fleet!
取消发射！我们可以用那个火箭将火星舰队引开！
Don't you see? Poor Fewsham deliberately
let us overhear their homing signal.
你没明白吗？可怜的 Fewsham 有意让我们听到了他们的引导信号
We can imitate that signal
with a homing device in the satellite!
我们可以用一个引导装置模拟那个信号, 再把引导装置装进火箭里
Commander Radnor, top priority message
to satellite launching site!
我是指挥官 Radnor, 给火箭发射场发送最高优先级的消息！
- Cancel launch! Repeat, Cancel launch!
- (COMPUTER) Message understood.
- 取消发射！重复, 取消发射！  - 消息已收到
If we can deflect their armada,
half our battle is won!
如果我们能把他们的舰队引开, 这场仗我们就赢了一半了
- But still, that fungus stuff is everywhere.
- We solved that one with H2O - water!
- 但是, 那些泡沫还是到处都是  - 我们用H2O解决那个问题了 - 水！
Water? Well, all we need to do is to make it rain!
水？那, 我们唯一要做的就是造雨！
It's hopeless, Doctor!
You'll never get that thing going again!
完全没希望, 博士！你永远没法让那个东西重新正常工作
I'm not so sure, Jamie. After all,
it's only the controls that are damaged.
我可不那么肯定, Jamie．毕竟, 被毁坏的只有控制开关
The workings are all right.
主体还是没事的
If we can bypass the controls...
如果我们能绕过这些控制开关
Have you got your knife on you?
Lend it me, will you? Be careful.
你身上带着刀吗？借我一下, 好吗．小心一点
Thank you. There we are.
Now, what have we got here?
谢谢．这些好啦．现在, 看看情况怎么样了？
Ah, yes... Yes, yes.
啊, 对了...对, 对
Yes, well, it's just a question
of sorting this lot out. That's all.
是了, 好啦, 现在就是搞明白这个东西的问题了, 仅此而已
All is prepared, Grand Marshal.
都准备好了, 大元帅
I shall return to our ship to finalise invasion plans.
我将返回我们的飞船, 准备最后的入侵计划
Right, now then, Zoe, let's see what happens
when we try to connect these two together.
好了, 现在, Zoe, 我们来看看我们把这两个东西连在一起, 会发生什么
No, I don't think so somehow!
不, 我觉得不是这样！
What about these two?
这两个怎么样？
Ah! That's better! I think I've succeeded /?
啊！好多了！我觉得我已经成功了
in re-establishing one of these rain circuits, Jamie.
造雨线路已经重新连起来了, Jamie
Well, it's not raining yet!
但是, 还没有下雨啊！
Oh, Jamie! Weather Control is a very difficult technology.
哦, Jamie！气象控制是一项很难的技术
You can't expect immediate results.
你不能指望马上有结果
- Are you sure you're getting it right?
- Yeah, I hope so, Zoe.
- 你确定你搞对了吗？  - 是, 我期望是, Zoe
Just have to hope for the best. That's all.
只能期望能有最好结果, 就这样了
I must get on as there's another little job I want to do.
我必须得继续了, 还有另外一件小事我想要住做
We should have some nice heavy rain before long!
不久以后我们就会有漂亮的大雨了！
- Ah, there we are!
- Yes, the satellite.
- 啊, 我们来了  - 是的, 卫星
(ELDRED) Isn't that a beautiful sight!
这个景观是不是很漂亮！
We've finished and installed the homing device.
It's working perfectly.
我们已经制作完成了引导装置, 并安装上去了, 工作得相当好
Doctor, I know we're sending up a false signal,
博士, 我知道我们送上去了一个假的讯号
but aren't some of the Martian ships
bound to follow the right one?
但就不会有一些火星飞船会收到正确的讯号吗？
There isn't going to be a right one,
there's going to be only ours, the wrong one,
不会有正确的讯号的, 只会有我们的讯号, 错误的这个
and that's going to lead the entire Martian fleet
into an orbit round the sun!
它会把整个火星舰队引导为沿着太阳轨道飞行！
- What about Slaar's signal?
- Obviously that has to be stopped.
- 那 Slaar 的讯号会怎么样？ - 显然, 它会被停掉
- But how?
- Well, as soon as that satellite is up
- 怎么停掉？  - 哦, 一旦卫星上天
I shall T-Mat myself to the moon
and destroy their homing device.
我就会用 T-Mat 把自己传送到月球上, 毁了他们的引导设备
- They'll kill you on sight!
- No, I don't think so.
- 他们一看见你就会杀了你的！  - 不, 我不这么想
I rigged up an interesting device here.
我这里拼凑了一对很有意思的设备
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
(KELLY) There it is. It's in orbit.
那就是了, 它进轨道了
We're picking up the aliens' homing signal from the moon.
我们识别到外星人在月球上发出的引导讯号了
That means their invasion fleet is getting closer.
There's no time to lose.
那意味着他们的入侵舰队已经接近了．没时间可以浪费了
Are you quite clear? As soon as
I have succeeded destroying their signal,
你清楚了吗？一旦我成功破坏了他们的讯号
you must activate our signal in the satellite.
你必须激活我们在卫星上的讯号
- We'll be ready.
- Right, then I'll be off.
- 我们会准备好的  - 好, 那我启程了
- Doctor, do be careful, won't you?
- Don't worry, Zoe, I will.
- 博士, 千万小心, 好吗？  - 别担心, Zoe, 我会的
- Are you ready, Miss Kelly?
- Doctor, our control of T-Mat hasn't been tested!
- 准备好了吗, Kelly 小姐？  - 博士, 我们 T-Mat 控制还没有测试过
Then now's the time to test it!
那现在就是测试它的时候！
(TRILLING)
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING)
(TWO-TONE SIGNAL)
(SIGNAL GETS LOUDER)
(SIGNAL GETS QUIETER)
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
(SLAAR) No.
不
You...
你...
..over there.
..过去那边
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
I ordered you to be destroyed!
我命令过要消灭你的！
Well, you weren't very successful, were you?
但是, 你并不是太成功, 是吧？
Destroy that weapon!
毁灭那个武器！
(TRILLING BUZZ)
What is your purpose in coming here?
你来这里的目的是什么？
You don't expect me to tell you that, do you?
你没指望我会告诉你吧, 对吗？
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
The directional beam is still operative.
牵引光速仍然在工作
Yes. I'm afraid you were a little too quick for me.
是的, 看来你动作很快
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Are you capable of operating the T-Mat mechanism?
你有能力操作 T-Mat 装置吗？
Oh, no. I don't think I...
哦, 不, 我觉得不行...
Well, yes, perhaps I could get the hang of it.
哦, 可以, 也许我会找到窍门的
As long as you can be useful to us, you can live,
只要你对我们有用, 你就可以活着
but this time, there will be no escape.
但这一次, 你不可能逃走了
You will familiarise yourself with the T-Mat controls.
你先让自己熟悉一下 T-Mat 控制开关
Oh, thank you very much!
哦, 非常感谢！
You will not touch the controls until I give the order.
在我下命令之前, 你不可碰这些开关
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
- (KELLY) It's operating perfectly!
- Shoulf we wait till the Doctor got back?
- 工作得很完美！  - 我们是不是应该等博士回来？
The moon signal has disappeared, hasn't it?
月球发出的讯号已经消失了, 对吗？
That may be too atmospheric. As all we know
they're transmitting as strongly as ever.
这可能是大气层影响, 就我9没所知它们的传送强度跟以前一样
The moon signal was strong enough
before the Doctor left.
月球发出的讯号在博士出发之前就很强
- He must have succeeded.
- Then why hasn't he come back?
- 他肯定已经成功了  - 那他怎么还没回来？
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
When our Warriors arrive,
我们的勇士一到
you will transmit them to Earth
under my direction.
你就按我的指示把他们传送到地球上去
Yes. They haven't arrived yet.
Something still might go wrong.
好. 目前他们还没到, 还是有可能出岔子
- Nothing can go wrong now!
- There's many a slip between the cup and the lip.
- 没什么会出岔子  - 杯子要送到嘴边还不保准呢
If anything does go wrong,
you will be the first to die.
如果有什么事情出了岔子, 你就是第一个没命的
(TWO-TONE BEEP)
Scan closer!
近距离扫描！
If they are going to divert,
it should happen any moment now!
如果他们要转移, 应该就在这一会儿了
They're changing course!
他们改变航向了！
I think you're right!
我觉得你是对的
They're all following the satellite signal!
他们都跟随的都是卫星发出的讯号
The Doctor must succeeded!
He must turned off the Martians' signal.
博士肯定成功了！我肯定已经关掉了火星人的讯号
What's happening up there, then?
Why hasn't he come back?
上面到底发生了什么？他为什么还没回来？
Don't worry, Jamie. A squad of Security guards
armed with flame throwers are on their way here now.
别担心, Jamie. 一队手持火焰喷射器的警卫正朝这里赶来
As soon as they get here, we'll T-Mat them to the moon.
等他们一到这里, 我们就用 T-Mat 把他们传送到月球上去
- They'll be too late!
- You'll just have to be patient!
- 那就来不及了  - 你得有点耐心！
I'm sick of being patient! -- Zoe.
我已经等得不耐烦了 -- Zoe
- That T-Mat thing, do you know how it works?
- I think so. Why?
- T-Mat 那个东西, 你知道它怎么用吗？  - 我觉得知道, 怎么了？
- Could you T-Mat me back to the moon?
- Oh, no, Jamie, shouldn't you...
- 你能把我 T-Mat 回月球不？  - 噢, 不, Jamie, 你不是应该...
Look, either the Doctor's all right,
in which case we've no reason to worry
你看, 要么博士没事, 这种情况下我们完全不用担心什么
or he's in danger and he needs my help!
要么他有危险, 那他就需要我的帮助！
You have failed us, Slaar!
你辜负了我们, Slaar！
We shall all die!
我们都会死！
We're being pulled into the orbit of the sun!
我们被被拖入了太阳的轨道！
This is impossible!
这不可能！
The signal! There is no power!
这个讯号, 它能量不够！
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
You did this!
是你干的！
Yes. That signal has been going
no further than this control room.
是的, 那个讯号跑不出这件控制室
But they were receiving my signal!
而他们接收到的是我的讯号！
Not your signal - ours.
不是你们的 - 我们的
You sent a signal...
你们发送了一个讯号...
..from Earth?
...从地球上发出的？
We sent up a satellite.
我们送上去一个卫星
That signal has sent your fleet into a false orbit!
那个讯号把你你们的舰队送入了错误的轨道！
The heat of the sun will kill them!
太阳的热量会杀死他们的！
You have destroyed our entire fleet!
你毁灭了我们整只舰队！
You tried to destroy an entire world.
你也试图毁灭一整个世界
Earth will still die!
地球还是会死！
The fungus will take the oxygen from your atmosphere!
真菌泡沫会把里面大气中的氧气都吸走！
I'm afraid you've failed there, too.
恐怕你们在那里也失败了
We can destroy the fungus.
我们能消灭真菌泡沫
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Kill him!
杀了他！
DOCTOR!
博士！
Jamie! Look out!
Jamie,小心！
(TRILLING BUZZ)
Creag an tuire!
Jamie! The light terminal!
Jamie！那个光终端！
Well done, Jamie!
干得好, Jamie！
Oh, goodness me! Jamie, thank you very much!
噢, 老天！Jamie, 非常感谢你！
Now then, we must T-Mat ourselves back to Earth.
现在, 我们得把我们自己 T-Mat 回地球了
(THUNDERCLAP)
(COMPUTER) Widespread rainfall throughout the country.
全国普降暴雨
Some flooding but none serious.
Fungus rapidly disappearing.
部分地方受淹, 但情况都不严重. 真菌迅速消失
Weather Control Bureau coming back into operation.
气象控制局已经恢复运行
World food shortages partially relieved,
全球出现的食物短缺已经得到部分缓解
now T-Mats are becoming operational again.
现在 T-Mat 正在恢复运转
Message to Commander Radnor
from the Security Council of the United Nations -
联合国安全理事会给指挥官 Radnor 发来消息：
-  Congratulations.
- All right. Just discontinue report.
- 祝贺！ - 好了, 停止播报吧
So you DID know what you were doing
at the Weather Control Bureau!
这么说在气象控制中心的时候, 你还真知道你在干什么？
Zoe, of course I did.
Zoe, 我当然知道
Well, it took long enough to work!
但是, 要这么长时间才生效啊！
Well, the rain seems dispose of the fungus well enough.
好, 这雨消除真菌的效果似乎很不错
Now the next thing to do is
to get T-Mat fully operational again.
现在接下来要做的事情, 就是让 T-Mat 完全恢复运转
Yes, when Moon Relay is repaired,
we must check over the equipment .
是. 等月球中转站修复之后, 我们必须全面检查设备
and build in safeguards. From now on,
T-Mat must be entirely controlled from Earth.
添加安全保护机制. 从今往后, T-Mat 必须完全由地球控制
Oh, surely you've learned not to
put all your eggs in one basket!
噢, 还以为你们已经汲取了教训, 不把所有鸡蛋放在同一个篮子里呢
T-Mat itself is perfectly effective!
T-Mat 自身是完全高效的！
You need a secondary transportation system,
a fleet of rockets on permanent stand by!
你需要一个后备系统, 一堆的火箭永久待命！
- There's no need to go to such lengths.
- It's a question of common sense!
- 没有必要非这么大劲  - 这是个常识的问题！
I'm sure the Doctor will agree with me! Doctor...
我肯定博士会赞同我的观点！博士...
(JAMIE) You didn't have to make it
rain as hard as all that!
你没必要让雨下得这么大！
Oh, Jamie, some of you is just never satisfied!
噢, Jamie, 有些人怎么总是不知足呢？
What did you rush us back here for?
为什么催我们回来这里？
Oh, you know, questions and explanations
are very difficult. Come on!
噢, 你也知道, 问问题答问题都是很麻烦的事情. 快点
- Where are we going now?
- It's no good asking him.
- 我们现在要去哪儿？  - 问他也没有用
He's no more idea than the man in the moon!
他并不比月球上那个人知道得多！
I heard that, Jamie! Come on!
我可听见了, Jamie！快点！